Finding Aid for the Paul Slentz Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Paul Slentz Collection
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0397
.42 linear_feet
Biographical Note
Paul Slentz received from Vanderbilt a Master’s degree in 1979 and a Masters of Divinity degree in 1998.
He was active in the non-violent protests concerning the hosting of the Davis Cup Tennis Tournaments at Vanderbilt University in the spring of 1978 and also in the Tenn Care Health Care Funding Crisis in 2004 and 2005.
He is a pastor in the United Methodist Church in Nashville, Tennessee.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection 0.42 linear feet (1 Hollinger box) contains materials relating to South Africa and Apartheid and in particular to The Davis Cup tennis championship that was held in Nashville at Vanderbilt in the spring of 1978. These papers were collected by Paul L. Slentz while he was a graduate student at Vanderbilt during the years 1977-1979.
- Correspondence and other papers
  - Paul Slentz - South Africa and Vanderbilt University (Folder 1)
- Vanderbilt University Publications
  - The Vanderbilt Hustler, - Feb. 3, 1978; Feb. 7, 1978; Feb. 10, 1978 (Folder 2)
  - The Vanderbilt Hustler, Feb. 17, 1978; Feb. 21, 1978; Feb. 24, 1978 (Folder 3)
  - The Vanderbilt Hustler, March 14, 1978; March 20, 1978 (Folder 4)
  - The Vanderbilt Hustler, April 7, 1978; April 11, 1978; April 21, 1978; April 25, 1978; April 28, 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Calendar, April 10 - April 16, 1978; Versus, April 1978 (Folder 6)
  - “South Africa: Living in Fear” written by Paul Slentz for Prospectus, Vol. xxi, No. 8, March 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Prospectus - Vanderbilt Divinity School, Vol. xxi, no. 8, March 1978; Vol. xxii, No. 1, September 1978 (Folder 8)
- Other publications
  - “Mass Media and Race Relations - Report of a Consultation” a report, Nashville, Tennessee, May 21 -22, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - The Militant, Vol. 42, No. 10, March 17, 1978 (Folder 10)
  - Newsletter - Edgehill United Methodist Church, Nashville, Tennessee, July 1978 (Folder 11)
  - “South Africa Fact Sheet”; “The Krugerrand: Facts about South Africa’s Gold Coin”; “ Southern Africa Literature List 1977”; “ACOA Action News, Fall 1977” (Folder 12)
- Printed Materials
  - Flyers - The Davis Cup - South Africa - Apartheid - Vanderbilt University (Folder 13)
  - Flyers - “ What is Apartheid?” and others - the Davis Cup - South Africa -Apartheid - Vanderbilt University (Folder 14)
  - The Davis Cup - South Africa - Apartheid - Vanderbilt University (Folder 15)
  - The Davis Cup - South Africa - Apartheid - Vanderbilt University (Folder 16)
  - The Davis Cup - South Africa - Apartheid - Sports (Folder 17)
  - The Davis Cup - South Africa - Apartheid (Folder 18)
  - TCAA (TN Coalition Against Apartheid) Report, April 1978; “South Africa” (Folder 19)
  - Southern Africa - ”The Rhodesian Settlement: Sell Out or Solution?” (Folder 20)
  - Various issues (Folder 21)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - The Tennessean - “Davis Bid May Reach Vandy’s Lamb”, Feb. 12, 1978 (Folder 22)
  - “S. Africa’s Race Policies Stirring Campus Activists”, March 19, 1978
- “Churches Curb Africa Business
  - “Why Break Exim Links to Apartheid”; “Biko’s Last Days”; “ A No-Fault Verdict”; Review of Biko in the New York Times, April 30 1978 (Folder 23)
- Other
  - Anti-Apartheid Song - Words (Folder 24)
  - Cassette Recording - Paul Slentz - the Davis Cup - South Africa - Apartheid - Vanderbilt University (Folder 25)